

□+1 (973) 738-0939 | ■ kevin.jiang@columbia.edu | ★ https://kevinj.io/ | ☑ https://github.com/kevinyjiang

About Me ____

Curiosity and a wide-range of interests are central to who I am as a Software Engineer. I have experience bringing full stack projects from planning to production and I'm deeply passionate about the intersection of design and artificial intelligence. Outside of work, I love exploring the latest advances in Music Machine Learning, working freelance photography gigs, and performing at jazz jam sessions around the city.

Education

Columbia University

New York, NY

B.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | GPA: 3.8

May 2020

• Coursework: Applied Deep Learning, Strategic Design, Computer Vision, Computer Graphics, Artificial Intelligence, Natural Language Processing

Work Experience _____

Simple Fractal New York, NY

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

September 2021 - Present

- Built scheduling service for a healthcare client automating manual workflows for over 10,000 nursing shifts per month. Leveraged cloud technologies like AWS lambdas and step functions to parallelize and deploy solutions. Iterated on a shift matching algorithm based on nurse qualifications and availability.
- · Contributed over 10 features across 2 separate teams. Technologies included React, Redux, Django, PostgreSQL, NodeJS, Puppeteer.
- On-boarded 2 new hires and guided them through a basic automation project that is now in production. Wrote scope of work documents and conducted client discovery calls for this and various other features.

Harmony Cloud New York, NY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

December 2020 - May 2021

- React Native app based on an algorithm that generates unpredictable yet compelling chord progressions following the rules of Western music theory.
- Worked with GRAMMY-nominated musician Stefon Harris to prototype and implement educational use cases for the algorithm.

Bank of New York Mellon New York, NY

PRODUCT DESIGN INTERN

June 2018 - August 2018

- Built a prototype data visualization tool with Microsoft HoloLens, demonstrating tangible business applications of augmented reality.
- · Wireframed dashboards for a big data product (Asset Strategy View) generating market intelligence across multiple business lines.

Columbia Photography Association

New York, NY

PRESIDENT

December 2015 - May 2019

- Expanded our clientele to include notable organizations like the United Nations and Lincoln Center, maintained relations with regulars across NYC.
- · Coordinated over 150 photography contracts per semester, oversaw 7 board members and dozens of student photographers.
- Built full stack web application to automate our job-handling and book-keeping workflows (MERN stack).

Skills

Tools

NodeJS, React/Redux, Django, AWS, SQL, Puppeteer, Unity, UNIX, Git/Github, TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV

Languages Python, JavaScript, C, C++, C#, Java, HTML/CSS

Projects_

Summer 2022 C++ Ray Tracer, Renders photo-realistic 3D scenes with recursive ray tracing implemented in C++. Optimized with bounding

 $volume\ hierarchies\ (logarithmic\ time\ complexity\ search\ tree).\ Capable\ of\ anti-aliasing,\ motion\ blur,\ diffuse\ shading,\ reflection,$

refraction, and defocus blur/depth of field.

Spring 2020 Jazz Transformer, Attention-based neural networks to generate authentic, nuanced jazz music. Compiled a jazz MIDI data set

using a state-of-the-art transcription model called Onsets and Frames. Performed transfer learning on a base transformer

model trained on classical music. Used TensorFlow and Google Magenta.

Summer 2019 Scriber, React Native app that uses Google Natural Language API to provide real-time speech-to-text transcription for

lecturers, tour guides, and other groups. Won first place at Horizons Summer Immersive Hackathon.